Amos 'n' Andy Radio Program Scripts
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Amos 'n' Andy Radio Program Scripts 1928-1937
MSS18267
Amos 'n' Andy (Radio Program)
420 items 10 containers 4 linear feet 9 microfilm reels
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Radio program. Scripts of the Amos ‘n’ Andy radio program.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
Subjects
Radio programs.; Radio scripts.
Titles
Amos 'n' Andy (Radio program)
Administrative Information
Provenance
The scripts of the Amos ‘n’ Andy radio program were transferred from the Library of Congress Copyright Office in 1968. A microfilm edition of the material was transferred in 1969.
Access and Restrictions
The Amos 'n' Andy Radio Program Scripts are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of these papers is available on nine reels. Consult a reference librarian in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan.
Scope and Content Note
The scripts of the Amos ‘n Andy radio program consist of scripts submitted to the Library of Congress Copyright Office between 1928 and 1937 and organized and filmed chronologically by date of broadcast.
The first radio program to be distributed by syndication in the United States, Amos ‘n’ Andy originated from station WMAQ in Chicago in 1928. It was written and voiced by white actors Freeman Gosden and Charles Correll performing minstrel-style as African-American characters located first in Chicago and later in Harlem. The program ran on the NBC Blue Network as a nightly serial beginning in 1929 and was soon distributed nationally to a large and expanding audience around the country.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged chronologically.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm80018267
Container List
Available on microfilm shelf no. 16,579 (negative no. 14,469)
- 1928 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - Mar. 19-Dec. 17 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - Dec. 18-31 (Box 2, Reel 1-2)
- 1929 (Box 2, Reel 1-2)
- 1930 (Box 2, Reel 1-2)
  - Jan. 1-2 (Box 2, Reel 1-2)
  - Jan. 3-Dec. 16 (Box 3,, Reel 2-3)
  - Dec. 17-31 (Box 4, Reel 3-4)
- 1931 (Box 4, Reel 3-4)
- 1932 (Box 4, Reel 3-4)
  - Jan. 1-2 (Box 4, Reel 3-4)
  - Jan. 4-Dec. 30 (Box 5, Reel 4-5)
- 1933 (Box 5, Reel 4-5)
  - Jan. 25-Dec. 30 (Box 5, Reel 4-5)
  - Jan. 25-Dec. 29 (Box 6, Reel 5-6)
- 1934 (Box 6, Reel 5-6)
  - Jan. 1-23 (Box 6, Reel 5-6)
  - Jan. 24-Dec. 31 (Box 7, Reel 6-7)
- 1935 (Box 7, Reel 6-7)
  - Jan. 1-Apr. 23 (Box 7, Reel 6-7)
  - Apr. 24-Dec. 31 (Box 8, Reel 7-8)
- 1936 (Box 8, Reel 7-8)
  - Jan. 1-Mar. 24 (Box 8, Reel 7-8)
- 1936 (Box 9, Reel 8)
  - Mar. 25-Dec. 31 (Box 9, Reel 8)
- 1937 (Box 10, Reel 8-9)